const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the most common site of ectopic pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Abdominal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Intramural uterine tube","bool":false},{"option":"Ampulla of the uterine tube","bool":true},{"option":"Isthmus of the fallopian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Rectouterine pouch","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A young lady presents with irregular vaginal bleeding. She is concerned for her health because her mother had cervical carcinoma. The gynecologist advises a pap smear testing which reveals cervical intraepithelial neoplasia. Cervical intraepithelial neoplasia is strongly associated with which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Herpes simplex virus","bool":false},{"option":"Cytomegalovirus","bool":false},{"option":"Ureaplasma urealyticum","bool":false},{"option":"Human papilloma virus","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 22-year-old obese, married nulliparous woman visits a gynecologist for irregular menstrual cycles for the past 1 year. On examination, it was found that she has hirsutism, alopecia, and acanthosis nigricans. Her ultrasound shows multiple fluid-filled sacs in the ovary. What does this indicate?","answers":[{"option":"Primary infertility","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrioses","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine fibroid","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 3-month-old male infant is brought to the outpatient department (OPD) for a routine check-up. On thorough examination, it is found that he has cryptorchidism. Which of the following best describes the condition?","answers":[{"option":"Enlarged testes in the scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Agenesis of testes","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of fluid in the testes","bool":false},{"option":"Two testes in each scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Testes fail to descend into the scrotum","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 46-year-old female presents with a history of infection in her perineal region. On comprehensive examination, it was found that the superior boundary of superficial perineal space is torn. Which structure is most likely to be injured?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Colle's fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Deep perineal fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is a remnant of paramesonephric duct in males?","answers":[{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false},{"option":"Appendix of testis","bool":true},{"option":"Duct of epididymis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is a common intermediate in the estrogen synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Corticosterone","bool":false},{"option":"11-deoxycorticosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":true},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the source of human chorionic gonadotropin hormone in a woman in whom fertilization has occurred two weeks before?","answers":[{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Embryo","bool":true}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common contraceptive method used in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Contraceptive ring","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"The oral contraceptive pill","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":true},{"option":"Intrauterine device (IUD)","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which one of the following represents the female pelvis with a greater transverse diameter of the outlet than the anteroposterior diameter?","answers":[{"option":"Gynecoid pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Dolicocephalic pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Android pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Platypelloid pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Mesatipellic pelvis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is used to detect pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the primary source of progesterone in late pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Graafian follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"During model studies, the students were discussing the boundaries of the ischiorectal fossa. One student pointed out the structure forming its medial wall. Which structure forms the medial wall of the ischiorectal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Levator ani","bool":false},{"option":"External anal sphincter","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator internus muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Urogenital diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which one of the following best describes the components of reproductive health?","answers":[{"option":"Public health, maternal health and contraception","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal health, child health and diseases of females","bool":false},{"option":"Health of youth, contraception, abortion, and sexually transmitted diseases","bool":false},{"option":"General health of public, abortion and contraception","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal health, abortion, and contraception","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Ovulation occurs in response to which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The proliferation of the corpus luteum is promoted by prolactin which stimulates the production of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thyrotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Somatomedin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following parts of the ductal system of the male reproductive system has a pseudostratified epithelial lining with some cells having sparse stereocilia?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":true},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false},{"option":"Ducts opening in prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Ducts opening in seminal vesicle","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following increases in case of damage to the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":true},{"option":"Anti-diuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone (GH)","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of these immunoglobulins can cross the placental barrier?","answers":[{"option":"IgG","bool":true},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The secretion of inhibin is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which type of cells are present in breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"Mast cells and plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils and macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Red blood cells and plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells and reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells and reticulocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Hemoglobin and hematocrit levels are at their lowest levels at which stage of pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Ninth month","bool":false},{"option":"Seventh month","bool":true},{"option":"First trimester","bool":false},{"option":"Second month","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth month","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Androstenedione contains how many carbons?","answers":[{"option":"20","bool":false},{"option":"14","bool":false},{"option":"16","bool":false},{"option":"19","bool":true},{"option":"17","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the WHO recommended duration for exclusive breastfeeding?","answers":[{"option":"6 months","bool":true},{"option":"4 months","bool":false},{"option":"3 months","bool":false},{"option":"2 years","bool":false},{"option":"1 year","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Higher than normal levels of progesterone are found in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Anovulatory cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal death","bool":false},{"option":"Amenorrhea","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"In granulosa cells of follicles, testosterone is converted to beta-estradiol. Which of the following enzymes is important for this conversion?","answers":[{"option":"Isomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatase","bool":true},{"option":"Oxygenase","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydratase","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of these follicles is seen in the prepubertal stage?","answers":[{"option":"Atretic follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Growing/preantral follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the major form of estrogen produced from menarche till menopause?","answers":[{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Beta-estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Esterol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is primarily a prolactin inhibiting factor?","answers":[{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Haloperidol","bool":false},{"option":"Metoclopramide","bool":false},{"option":"Somatotropin","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"When the internal iliac artery is damaged, what anastomosis provides compensation for blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral and middle rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral and interior rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral and superior rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and middle rectal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral and middle colic artery","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"During ligation of the uterine artery, which of the following structures have the chance of being ligated along with it?","answers":[{"option":"Ureter","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ilioinguinal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which is not true about Sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"Have gap junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Nourish developing spermatids","bool":false},{"option":"Are found in seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Are phagocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Are large and have irregular outlines","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following aptly defines gender?","answers":[{"option":"Difference in health problem","bool":false},{"option":"Biological differences","bool":false},{"option":"External appearance","bool":false},{"option":"How a patient identifies themselves","bool":false},{"option":"How a patient identifies themselves according to their roles in society","bool":true}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Major contribution to semen is from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":true},{"option":"Epdidymis","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral gland","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Tearing of the pelvic diaphragm during childbirth can lead to the paralysis of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sphincter urethrae","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Sphincter ani externus","bool":false},{"option":"Piriformis","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones are involved in the luteal phase?","answers":[{"option":"Only estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Only progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone and luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone only","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone and estrogen","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is a part of the urogenital diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Deep transverse perineal muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial transverse perineal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is an intermediate in the biogenic synthesis of adrenocortical hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is wrong about the Sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"They form tight junctions and connective adhesion molecules with neighboring Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"They are not present in the interstitial space","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells have darker nuclei as compared to primary spermatogonia","bool":true},{"option":"They secrete a compound called Mullerian inhibiting factor (MIF)","bool":false},{"option":"They provide nourishment to primary spermatogonia","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is the first hormone secreted by the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following lymph nodes do testes drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Para-aortic lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The lower one-third of the vagina drains into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"The common and internal iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"The superficial inguinal and perirectal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding prostate?","answers":[{"option":"70% of prostate cancer originates in the peripheral zone","bool":false},{"option":"Central zone is around ejaculatory ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior lobe is mainly muscular","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior lobe is mainly fibrous","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional zone surrounds urethral meatus","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the vaginal mucosa?","answers":[{"option":"It is lined by stratified squamous keratinized epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Its cells secrete lactic acid","bool":false},{"option":"It does not possess elastic fibers","bool":false},{"option":"It is lubricated by the glands located in the cervix","bool":true},{"option":"It is lined by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"During the 5th week, what is formed by the mesenchymal proliferation on the medial side of mesonephros?","answers":[{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Testes","bool":false},{"option":"Genital ridge","bool":true},{"option":"Metanephric blastema","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is not required for fertilization?","answers":[{"option":"Capacitation","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol from seminal vesicle","bool":true},{"option":"Sperm and ovum","bool":false},{"option":"Acrosomal enzymes","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is not true about the oviduct?","answers":[{"option":"Peg cells are ciliated","bool":true},{"option":"The muscle layer consists of an outer longitudinal layer and inner circular layer.","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated cells are non-functional","bool":false},{"option":"The proximal part is called isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Intramural portion extends through the uterine wall","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following drains into the portal vein?","answers":[{"option":"Middle rectal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal vein","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal vein","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is more likely to get damaged during catheterization?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatic urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy urethra","bool":true},{"option":"Glans penis","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus cavernosum","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following ensures storage and maturation of sperms, and joins the ductus deferens?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":true},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Rete testis","bool":false},{"option":"Penis","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of these increases reception of cervical mucus to the sperm movement?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatic fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":true},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"HCl","bool":false},{"option":"Mucus","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Ideally, when should intrauterine devices (IUDs) be implanted?","answers":[{"option":"During menstruation","bool":true},{"option":"Before menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"After menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Mid cycle","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is odd regarding Graffian follicle?","answers":[{"option":"Cumulus oophorus","bool":false},{"option":"Primary oocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Zona pellucida","bool":false},{"option":"Liquor folliculi","bool":false},{"option":"Theca folliculi","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"As a result of damage to the spongy urethra, where does the urine start to escape into?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial perineal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus cavernosum","bool":false},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following protects young women against heart disease?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following represents the stage in which the follicle is arrested in the prophase-I of the first meiotic division?","answers":[{"option":"Mature follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Graffian follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of these is an effect of progesterone on the uterine endometrium?","answers":[{"option":"It increases myometrial excitability","bool":false},{"option":"It increases glycogen deposition in the glandular epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It causes regression of spiral arteries","bool":false},{"option":"It converts glands from coiled to tubular forms","bool":false},{"option":"It works synergistically with estrogen to increase proliferation","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A fetus is born with an enlarged clitoris and fused labia majora/minora. Ultrasound confirms that the fetus is female. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"5-alpha reductase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Ovotesticular disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian dysgenesis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following features is the most prominent and can be used to identify fallopian tubes?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Highly branched mucosal longitudinal folds","bool":true},{"option":"Muscularis has three layers; longitudinal, circular, and oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A deficiency of iodine in maternal blood can cause which condition in a child?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Regarding the blood-testis barrier, which of the following is the most inappropriate statement?","answers":[{"option":"Formed by contact of lateral processes of Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Formed by Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Is present in adluminal compartment","bool":false},{"option":"Only present in basal compartment of seminiferous tubules","bool":true},{"option":"Prevents autoimmune reaction of secondary spermatocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the meaning of empowerment?","answers":[{"option":"Control over others","bool":false},{"option":"Control over environment","bool":false},{"option":"Control over community","bool":false},{"option":"Control over society","bool":false},{"option":"Control over one's own life","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A doctor after a thorough examination diagnosed a patient with benign prostatic hyperplasia. He gives him 5-alpha reductase inhibitor to decrease which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Angiotensinogen conversion to angiotensin","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin conversion to angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone conversion to dihydrotestosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone conversion to angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone conversion to 5-alpha reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A sudden decrease in the circulatory levels of which placental hormone indicates a nonviable pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A diabetic patient comes to the clinic with complaints of high-grade fever and a purulent discharge from a small opening in the perineal region. After examination, a diagnosis of abscess in the ischio-anal fossa is made. Which of the following structures forms the medial boundary of the ischioanal fossa?","answers":[{"option":"External anal sphincter","bool":true},{"option":"Obturator internus","bool":false},{"option":"Sacro-tuberous ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Gluteal maximus","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A newly married female patient comes to the gynecology consultant clinic with complaints of pain during micturition and a purulent discharge from the vagina. After examination, a diagnosis of bacterial infection is made. It causes the obstruction of the paraurethral glands. Inflamed glands are homologous with which of the following structures in males?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate","bool":true},{"option":"Scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Glans penis","bool":false},{"option":"Penis","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral glands","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A female patient comes to the gynecology outpatient department with complaints of pain and swelling in the external genitalia which increases while walking or weight lifting. On examination, a diagnosis of inguinal hernia is made due to the termination of the round ligament of the uterus in the external genitalia. The above-mentioned ligament terminates in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Clitoris","bool":false},{"option":"Mons pubis","bool":false},{"option":"Labia majora","bool":true},{"option":"Bulb of vestibule","bool":false},{"option":"Labia minora","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the main supports of the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Pubo-cervical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Tone of levator ani","bool":false},{"option":"Sacro-cervical ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament of uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Perineal body","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following arteries in males is replaced by a vaginal artery in females?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior vesical artery","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior gluteal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Umbilical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior vesical artery","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Ovarian arteries arise from which of the following vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Descending thoracic aorta","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Abdominal aorta","bool":true},{"option":"Renal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is inappropriate regarding histological features of the early proliferative phase of the endometrium?","answers":[{"option":"Thick stroma","bool":true},{"option":"Epithelial cells acquire cilia and microvilli","bool":false},{"option":"Thin walled endometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Thin muscular wall","bool":false},{"option":"Fairly sparse and straight glands","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Ovaries of a young girl who has not yet reached puberty contain which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary oocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Atretic follicles","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicles","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following represents a fold of peritoneum extending from the ovaries to the pelvic wall containing blood vessels and nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Mesovarium","bool":false},{"option":"Utero-ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Mesosalpinx","bool":false},{"option":"Suspensory ligament of ovary","bool":true},{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following epithelial transition is seen between the vagina and the cervix?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified squamous to simple columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Simple columnar to simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous to stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous to simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Simple squamous to stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following cells are present in the interstitium of the testes?","answers":[{"option":"Primary spermatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary spermatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Spermatid","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following statements is inappropriate regarding the corpora amylacea?","answers":[{"option":"Found in prostatic alveoli","bool":false},{"option":"Condensations of secretory products of prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Appear as concentric lamellar bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Number increases with age","bool":false},{"option":"Number decreases with age","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which stage of the follicle is marked by the conversion of cells surrounding the oocyte from squamous to cuboidal cells?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Growing follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Mature follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":true}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"During the development of the male reproductive system, gonadal cords or primitive sex cords develop in the gonadal ridges. These cords give rise to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica albuginea","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":true},{"option":"Ductus deferens","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The mesonephric ducts or Wolfian ducts play an important role in the development of male genital ducts. Secretions from which of the following have a crucial part in the normal development of these ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Mesenchymal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Spermatogonia","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial cells of Leydig","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"In an embryo with XX sex chromosome genotype, fallopian tubes, uterus, and the vagina is formed in the absence of Mullerian inhibiting factor. Which of the following gives rise to these structures?","answers":[{"option":"Paramesonephric ducts","bool":true},{"option":"Mesonephric ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary sex cords","bool":false},{"option":"Mesonephric tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Primary sex cords","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"From which of the following does the external urethral meatus develop?","answers":[{"option":"Scrotal swellings","bool":false},{"option":"Anal folds","bool":false},{"option":"Urethral folds","bool":false},{"option":"Phallus","bool":false},{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is not a derivative of the Wolffian ducts?","answers":[{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":true},{"option":"Seminal vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"At which stage of the menstrual cycle does the progesterone rise to its highest level?","answers":[{"option":"At the start of the luteinizing hormone (LH) surge","bool":false},{"option":"Just before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Mid follicular phase","bool":false},{"option":"At the end of menses","bool":false},{"option":"In the early luteal phase","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"At which of the following stages of the menstrual cycle does the estrogen rise to its highest value?","answers":[{"option":"Middle of luteal phase","bool":false},{"option":"In the middle of menses","bool":false},{"option":"Early luteal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Just before ovulation","bool":true},{"option":"Middle of follicular phase","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which cells of the ovary secrete estrogen in the follicular phase of the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial follicular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cells in theca externa","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus luteal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cells in theca interna","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"At the time of parturition, there is increased contractility of the uterine walls. This is said to be induced by the increased levels of estrogen near the end of the pregnancy.  How does the estrogen increase contractility of the walls?","answers":[{"option":"It increases the number of smooth muscle fibers","bool":false},{"option":"By increasing the gap junctions","bool":true},{"option":"By increasing nerves","bool":false},{"option":"It increases the number and sensitivity of receptors","bool":false},{"option":"It increases the vascularity of the uterine wall","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Suckling action of a baby on breasts with the help of which of the following two hormones increases milk production and secretion?","answers":[{"option":"Follicular stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin and relaxin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin and oxytocin","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen and progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone and dihydrotestosterone","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is responsible for the development of ducts and the deposition of fat in the stromal tissue of the breast?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is responsible for the development of the lobules and alveoli in the breast?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is produced in pregnancy and almost exclusively in the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Beta human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormonal scenarios happens towards the end of pregnancy and is partly responsible for increased contractility of the uterine walls?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen to progesterone ratio increases","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen induces luteinizing hormone surge","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone is constant","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen continues to increase","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone to estrogen ratio increases","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Prolactin is classified into which of the following biochemical groups?","answers":[{"option":"Steroid","bool":false},{"option":"Amino acid","bool":false},{"option":"Polypeptide","bool":true},{"option":"Glycoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Protein molecule","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Receptors for the estrogen are present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"In endoplasmic membranes","bool":false},{"option":"In cytoplasm","bool":true},{"option":"In the Golgi apparatus","bool":false},{"option":"In the mitochondria","bool":false},{"option":"In the cell membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The anterior pituitary gland secretes many hormones which regulate the functions of other glands in the body. Which of these hormones is not secreted from the anterior pituitary?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenocorticotropic hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid stimulating hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones increases at puberty to initiate the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadotropin releasing hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Esterogen","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes catalyzes the synthesis of estrogen from androgen in circulation?","answers":[{"option":"17-α-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"3-β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol desmolase complex","bool":false},{"option":"17-β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":true},{"option":"5-α-reductase","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Raised luteinizing hormone and decreased testosterone levels in the serum indicate the failure of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior pituitary","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior pituitary","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"As menstruation ends, estrogen levels in the blood rise rapidly. What is the source of estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Endometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Stromal cells of ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Developing follicles","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following enzymes is required to convert testosterone to estradiol?","answers":[{"option":"Lyase","bool":false},{"option":"Oxygenase","bool":false},{"option":"Isomerase","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatase","bool":true}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Administration of which vitamins will prevent the neural tube defects from occurring?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B9","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin B5","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A  middle-aged female patient presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of on and off pelvic pain. She denies any abnormal vaginal discharge or other associated symptoms. Ultrasonography reveals the presence of multiple ovarian cystic lesions filled with clear fluid and most of them were around 2 centimeters in diameter. Which of the following cysts originates from unruptured Graffian follicles or from follicles that ruptured and immediately sealed?","answers":[{"option":"Follicular cyst","bool":true},{"option":"Endometrial cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Dermoid cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Cystadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A female patient presented with multiple whitish vaginal lesions. She also reported itching in the affected area but has no other comorbidity. Her gynecologist ordered a biopsy to help identify the underlying cause which was further diagnosed as squamous cell hyperplasia. Which of the following is a characteristic feature of the above-mentioned disorder?","answers":[{"option":"Disappearance of rete pegs","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperpigmented skin lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Acanthosis and hyperkeratosis","bool":true},{"option":"Increased atypia","bool":false},{"option":"Thinning of the epidermis","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A young female presented to the clinic with the complaint of irregular menstrual cycles. She was married for the last six years but was unable to conceive. Ultrasonography revealed multiple ovarian cysts. Which of the following is the main biochemical abnormality in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoandrogenism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperaldosteronism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperandrogenism","bool":true},{"option":"Hypoaldosteronism","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A middle-aged female presented to the clinic with complaints of irregular menstrual cycle and excessive body hair. She was unmarried and had hypertension for the last three years. Ultrasonography revealed multiple ovarian cysts. Which of the following biochemical abnormalities is associated with the polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS)?","answers":[{"option":"Reduced body weight","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid disease","bool":false},{"option":"Premature atherosclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Insulin deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Normal ovulation","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Various congenital anomalies may develop in the female genital tract during embryological development. Which of the following statements is correct regarding these anomalies?","answers":[{"option":"Uterus didelphys refers to the single uterus with two vaginas","bool":false},{"option":"Gartner duct cyst arise from the mesonephric duct and is present in the wall of the uterus.","bool":false},{"option":"Imperforate hymen is also called vaginal atresia","bool":false},{"option":"Diethylstilbestrol is associated with congenital anomalies and is still used.","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal adenosis refers to small residual patches of glandular epithelium in adult life","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"An unmarried teenage girl undergoes a secret abortion to get rid of unwanted pregnancy. The process was carried out by using dirty knitting needles. After one week she develops abdominal pain, fever, and purulent vaginal discharge. Which of the following statements is correct regarding the condition of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Most likely diagnosis is pelvic inflammatory disease due to multiple micro-organisms","bool":true},{"option":"Pyosalpinx and tubo-ovarian abscesses are extremely unlikely to occur","bool":false},{"option":"She can be treated with antipyretics and sent home","bool":false},{"option":"Complicated candida infection is the most common cause of this etiology","bool":false},{"option":"The smear made from this vaginal discharge would show Trichomonas vaginalis","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following represents the karyotype of a partial mole?","answers":[{"option":"Triploid","bool":true},{"option":"Haploid","bool":false},{"option":"Tetraploid","bool":false},{"option":"Diploid 46, XY","bool":false},{"option":"Diploid 46, XX","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 25-year-old married woman is brought to the emergency room with complaints of severe abdominal pain and vaginal bleeding. Her husband informs the doctor that she is 10 weeks pregnant and was scheduled to visit her doctor for an ultrasound but she could not go. Examination reveals severe pallor and acute abdomen. Ultrasound reveals the distended fallopian tubes and intraperitoneal hemorrhage. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pelvic inflammatory disease","bool":false},{"option":"Ruptured tubal pregnancy","bool":true},{"option":"Acute appendicitis","bool":false},{"option":"Threatened abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Pre-eclampsia","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most effective clinical contraceptive with the least chances of failure?","answers":[{"option":"Oral contraceptive pills","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine contraceptive device","bool":true},{"option":"Depo-Provera injection","bool":false},{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 56-year-old male is diagnosed with neurosyphilis. He never got treatment for the disease and knows nothing about the illness except for the fact that his friend told him not to tell anyone about the disease and not to visit the doctor as it is a disease that would bring shame to him. Which of the following played a major role as a barrier to seeking proper treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Lack of proper education regarding sexual and reproductive health","bool":true},{"option":"Fear of illness","bool":false},{"option":"Poverty","bool":false},{"option":"Illiteracy","bool":false},{"option":"Fear of doctor","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"You are having a conversation with your colleagues regarding the state of reproductive health in Pakistan which includes large family size, unwanted pregnancies, and high maternal and neonatal mortality rates. Which of the following is the major factor that leads to all of this?","answers":[{"option":"Socio-economical status","bool":false},{"option":"Poverty","bool":false},{"option":"Male domination","bool":false},{"option":"Illiteracy","bool":false},{"option":"Lack of education regarding reproductive health","bool":true}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 25-year-old para 2+0 presented to the outpatient department with the complaint of irregular vaginal bleeding. The duration of her cycle is 11 days occurring every 15 days. Which of the following accurately describes the above-mentioned condition?","answers":[{"option":"Oligomenorrhoea","bool":false},{"option":"Metrorrhagia","bool":false},{"option":"Polymenorrhagia","bool":true},{"option":"Menorrhagia","bool":false},{"option":"Polymenorrhoea","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 30-year-old para 3+0 presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of irregular vaginal bleeding. The duration of her menstrual flow is 10 days occurring after every 28 days. Which of the following terms is used for this pattern of bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"Metrorrhagia","bool":false},{"option":"Polymenorrhagia","bool":false},{"option":"Menorrhagia","bool":true},{"option":"Polymenorrhoea","bool":false},{"option":"Oligomenorrhoea","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 13-year-old presents to the outpatient department and has passed menarche 6 days ago. She is passing clots and is bleeding heavily. She experiences recurrent episodes of epistaxis and bleeding from her gums. Her hemoglobin is 5 g/dl. What would be the next step in the investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Diagnostic dilation and curettage procedure (D/C)","bool":false},{"option":"Transvaginal cholecystectomy (TVC)","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone profile","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":true},{"option":"Hysteroscopy","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 45-year-old para 1+0 is presents to the outpatient department with the complaint of irregular vaginal bleeding for the last 5 months. Pelvic ultrasound reveals an endometrial thickness of 1.5 centimeters but there is no abnormal uterine or adnexal mass. What would be your next step to investigate the case further?","answers":[{"option":"Hysteroscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone and luteinizing hormone profile","bool":false},{"option":"Transvaginal sonography (TVS)","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulation profile","bool":false},{"option":"Diagnostic dilation and curettage procedure (D/C)","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is responsible for the engorgement of breasts during early pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A woman presents to the clinic with the complaint of cessation of the menstrual cycle for the last 3 months. Previously she had regular menstruation occurring every 30th day and continued for 4 days. On what day of the cycle this woman is most likely to ovulate?","answers":[{"option":"30th day","bool":false},{"option":"14th day","bool":false},{"option":"28th day","bool":false},{"option":"16th day","bool":true},{"option":"7th day","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"What is the main source of the hormone maintaining the decidual nature of endometrium in the 24th week of the pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Placenta","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is the source of the hormone responsible for maintaining the decidual nature of the endometrial tissue during the 12th week of the pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":true},{"option":"Placenta","bool":false},{"option":"Pituitary gland","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following abnormalities is common between epispadias and hypospadias?","answers":[{"option":"Small prepuce","bool":false},{"option":"Abormal testicular development","bool":true},{"option":"Increased urinary tract infections","bool":false},{"option":"Association with 5α-reductase deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Exostrophy of bladder","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which enzyme is responsible for releasing DNA supercoils?","answers":[{"option":"DNA ligase","bool":false},{"option":"RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Topoisomerase","bool":true},{"option":"Helicase","bool":false},{"option":"Single strand DNA","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 35-year-old woman Para 2+0 presented in the outpatient department with a complaint of heavy menstrual bleeding. Bleeding above which of the following volumes will be categorized as heavy menstrual bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"200 ml","bool":false},{"option":"150 ml","bool":false},{"option":"50 ml","bool":false},{"option":"100 ml","bool":false},{"option":"80 ml","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following factors does not play a role in the normal development of testes?","answers":[{"option":"SRY gene","bool":false},{"option":"Mullerian inhibiting substance","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Y chromosome","bool":false},{"option":"Testes determining factor","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 25-year-old female para 1+0 presents to the clinic showing concern regarding the health of her newborn baby. The doctor suggests that she feed her baby milk with relatively lower casein, calcium, and lactalbumin but higher lactose for the better development of the nervous system and to reduce the risk of increased burden on the kidneys. Which milk is best for the growth of a newborn child?","answers":[{"option":"Breast milk","bool":true},{"option":"Formula milk","bool":false},{"option":"Camel milk","bool":false},{"option":"Goat milk","bool":false},{"option":"Cow milk","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following hormones is secreted by the placenta and is responsible for maintaining a pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"In which of the following does secondary meiosis occur?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary follicle","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial germ cell","bool":false},{"option":"Primary follicle","bool":false},{"option":"Primordial follicle","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following can be the reason for the continuous involuntary flow of urine from vagina?","answers":[{"option":"Vesico-uterine fistula that might develop after delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Perforation of bladder","bool":false},{"option":"Vesico-vaginal fistula that might develop after delivery","bool":true},{"option":"Ureterovaginal fistula which is congenital","bool":false},{"option":"Rectovaginal fistula","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is the most common complication of the intrauterine device method of contraception?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical injury","bool":false},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine perforation","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic infection","bool":false},{"option":"IUD expulsion","bool":true}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which one of the following is the convergence point where spermatic vessels and ductus deferens come together?","answers":[{"option":"External inguinal ring","bool":false},{"option":"Internal oblique arch","bool":false},{"option":"External spermatic fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Cremasteric fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Internal inguinal ring","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which one of the following ligaments prevents prolapse of the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Cardinal ligament and uterine axis","bool":true},{"option":"Iliococcygeus part of levator ani","bool":false},{"option":"Rectouterine fold of peritoneum","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Rectovesical fold of peritoneum","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which one of the following is the major aim of imparting knowledge regarding reproductive health?","answers":[{"option":"To live a more fulfilling life in terms of reproduction","bool":false},{"option":"So an individual can have broader choices in their life","bool":false},{"option":"To do family planning","bool":false},{"option":"To prevent the occurrence of sexually transmitted diseases","bool":true},{"option":"To prevent congenital diseases","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following is a condition in which veins draining any one side of the testis are dilated in the lateral scrotum and are optimistic for transillumination?","answers":[{"option":"Varicocele","bool":true},{"option":"Chylocele","bool":false},{"option":"Spermatocele","bool":false},{"option":"Hematocele","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocele","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A pediatrician notices a 4-year-old girl having stained underwear and grape-like masses coming out of the vestibule. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Endocervical polyps","bool":false},{"option":"Cervicitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vulvar intraepithelial neoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoma botryoides","bool":true}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 58-year-old post-menopausal woman presents with heavy bleeding and an adnexal mass. Histopathology reveals an increased gland-to-stroma ratio and the masses are well-circumscribed necrotic and show nuclear atypia. Which of the following is true for her condition?","answers":[{"option":"It is due to unopposed high progesterone levels","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnancy related bleeding should be ruled out","bool":false},{"option":"Mutations in PTEN tumor suppressor genes are common","bool":true},{"option":"This condition arises due to an untreated protozoal infection","bool":false},{"option":"It is due excessive oxytocin released by posterior pituitary","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 16-year-old girl is brought to the hospital with the complaint of delayed menarche. On examination, she has a webbed neck, a broad chest, and widely spaced inverted nipples. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Kallman syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Edward syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"William syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 17-year-old girl presented to the clinic with complaints of primary amenorrhea. She has well-developed breasts and a physical exam shows normal secondary sexual characteristics but a short vagina. The uterus is undetected and two inguinal masses are found instead. What is the most likely diagnosis for this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of SRY gene","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Mayer Rokitansky Küster Hauser (MRKH) syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A 15-year-old girl experiencing pelvic pain was examined and a mass was found in her ovaries. The mass on excision was white with necrotic patches and had primitive mesenchymal cells of cartilage, muscle tissue, and foci of neuroepithelial differentiation. What is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Leiomyosarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cell tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Brenner tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Dysgerminoma","bool":false},{"option":"Immature teratoma","bool":true}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"A post-menopausal woman having endometrial hyperplasia with increased gland-to-stroma ratio with atypia presented to the outpatient department. What advice would you give her?","answers":[{"option":"Advise her to go for hysterectomy due to risk of carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Pap smear after regular intervals","bool":false},{"option":"Ask her to come for checkup every five years","bool":false},{"option":"Prescribe high dose antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Reassure her that there is nothing to worry about","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Estrogen is secreted in high concentrations in which of the following phases of the menstrual cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Secretory phase","bool":false},{"option":"Fertilization","bool":false},{"option":"Peaks one day before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Proliferative phase","bool":true},{"option":"Menstrual phase","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"The process of spermatogenesis is controlled by negative feedback to the pituitary to decrease FSH. Which hormone inhibits the secretion of FSH?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibin","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"To perform the pudendal nerve block, the surgeon palpates a landmark on the ischium. Which of the following is an appropriate landmark?","answers":[{"option":"Ischial tuberosity","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial spine","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ramus","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial body","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ramus","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following lymph nodes drain the ovaries?","answers":[{"option":"Internal iliac lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Para aortic lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Mesenteric lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2021","question":"Which of the following chemical substances is a precursor to estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Aldosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Cholestrol","bool":false},{"option":"Cortisol","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":true}]}]
export default arr